Now, we briefly touched about virtual environments.
They are an important way of storing the dependencies
that your Python application requires,
creating that virtual environment will make
a self-contained folder that includes that full Python installation.
And it's going to allow you to install dependencies that are specific
to that application, and a specific version of Python,
without the possibility of messing up your global
version of Python, might not be the same version.
You're not going to have the same libraries
that you're using between different projects,
which is why isolating an virtual environment is very important.
You might see this shortened as virtual and for short.
A standard that you might see is a requirements.txt file that's included
with a Python project. It's a special file that we're going to use to tell
just Python's package manager command line tool,
which dependencies to install for this particular package.
The format is simple. You just put each dependency manually on one line
in this file. If you need to specify a specific version,
you can do double equals and put the version after the name of the library.
Or you can just install each dependency in your virtual environment using
pip directly. Once you've done that,
probably as you're building the application,
you can see which packages are present in your virtual environment
with a command called pip freeze.
You can pipe that into a requirements.txt file to generate that for you
automatically. Unfortunately, that also includes a lot of these sub-dependencies.
I prefer if I'm working on a simple project to manage these requirements.txt
files manually, but that's not important.
If you get a project with a requirements.txt file,
you can do a pip install dash in your virtual environment
to install all of the dependency specified in this file.